accruent.com 2019-08-28

# Accruent's Website Privacy Policy Statement | Accruent

  Español  |  Français  |  Deutsche  |  Português (Brazil)  |  Nederlands

* * *

_Effective Date: June 5, 2019_

## _STANDARD WORK_

THIS PRIVACY NOTICE APPLIES ONLY TO SITUATIONS WHERE THE GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR) AND RELATED EUROPEAN DATA PROTECTION LAWS GOVERN THE WAY ACCRUENT HANDLES, OR “PROCESSES”, YOUR PERSONAL DATA. THESE LAWS ARE MOST LIKELY TO APPLY WHENEVER A COMPANY IS ESTABLISHED IN EUROPE OR HANDLES THE PERSONAL DATA OF INDIVIDUALS WHO ARE LOCATED IN EUROPE.

THIS NOTICE DOES NOT APPLY TO OUR HANDLING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA IN THE HUMAN RESOURCES CONTEXT. A SEPARATE PRIVACY NOTICE APPLIES TO THESE SITUATIONS AND IS AVAILABLE FROM THE ACCRUENT HUMAN RESOURCES DEPARTMENT.

IF THIS NOTICE DOES APPLY TO HOW ACCRUENT HANDLES YOUR PERSONAL DATA, PLEASE READ IT CAREFULLY BECAUSE IT PROVIDES IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND EXPLAINS YOUR RIGHTS. IF THIS NOTICE DOES NOT APPLY TO HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND YOU HAVE RELATED QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS, WE INVITE YOU TO CONTACT US BY ANY OF THE METHODS LISTED AT THE BOTTOM OF THIS DOCUMENT.

### ACCRUENT PRIVACY NOTICE

Table of Contents  
---  
  
  * Who are we?
  * What does this privacy notice cover?
  * What personal data do we collect about you? 
  * Where do we collect personal data about you from? 
  * How and why do we use your personal data? 
  * How long do we keep your personal data? 
  * Who do we share your personal data with? 
  * What legal basis do we have for using your personal data? 
  * What happens if you do not provide us with the information we request or ask that we stop processing your information? 
  * Do we make automated decisions concerning you? 
  * Do we use Cookies to collect personal data on you? 
  * What about marketing? 
  * Where do we store your personal data? Do we transfer your personal data outside the EEA? 
  * How do we keep your personal data secure? 
  * What rights do you have in relation to the personal data we hold on you? 
  * How can you make a request to exercise your rights?
  * How will we handle a request to exercise your rights?
  * How can you contact us? 

Who are we?  
---  
  
We are Accruent of 11500 Alterra Parkway, Suite 110, Austin, TX 78758 USA you can contact us at [support@accruent.com](https://support@accreunt.com/) or by phone at 512.861.0726

We provide software solutions for managing physical resources - real estate, facilities and assets. This Privacy Notice explains how we use the personal data we hold on you as a current, former, or future customer, distributor, investor, creditor, advisor, website visitor, supplier, service provider, vendor, and the like.

We use your information as further explained in this Privacy Notice

Any links from our website to other websites will have their own privacy notices and terms.  
  
What does this Privacy Notice cover?  
---  
  
We at Accruent take your personal data seriously. This policy:

  * sets out the types of personal data that we collect about you;
  * explains how and why we collect and use your personal data;
  * explains how long we keep your personal data for;
  * explains when, why and with who we will share your personal data;
  * sets out the legal basis we have for using your personal data;
  * explains the effect of refusing to provide the personal data requested;
  * explains where we store your personal data and whether we transfer your data outside of the European Economic Area;
  * explains the different rights and choices you have when it comes to your personal data; and
  * explains how you can contact us.

What personal data do we collect about you?  
---  
  
We will collect certain personal information about you in the course of your relationship with us.

This information includes:

  * Contact Information, such as name, email address, and phone number
  * Demographic Information, such as Industry
  * Product Interest Preference
  * Information collected using CCTV cameras (only if you visit one of our premises that use this technology)

In exceptional cases we may also collect and process sensitive personal data about you, but only where we inform you in advance and you have given us your explicit consent.  
  
Where do we collect personal data about you from?  
---  
  
We may collect personal data about you from the following sources:

  * Directly from you. This is information you provide to us.
  * From an agent or third party acting on your behalf, e.g., from one of our recruitment agencies.
  * Through publicly available sources, such as LinkedIn or even by word of mouth.
  * Using CCTV cameras. Where we have cameras on our premises, your image and movements will be recorded.

How and why do we use your personal data?  
---  
  
We use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Respond to a request for a demonstration of our services
  * Send you product or industry information via marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Improve our web site and marketing efforts
  * Engage in certain transactions with you
  * Process certain transactions with you

We will not use your information for any other unrelated purposes unless we are required to do so by law.  
  
How long do we keep your personal data?  
---  
  
How long we keep your information will depend on the purpose for which we use it.

We only keep your information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice and to fulfill our legal obligations. We have internal rules that set out how long we retain information. What this means in practice will vary as between different types of information, and when we consider our approach we take into account any ongoing need for the information as well as our legal obligations, for example in relation to tax, health and safety, and potential or actual disputes or investigations.  
  
Who do we share your personal data with?  
---  
  
We may share your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities. We use other third parties such as an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf and an employment management provider and a credit card processing provider to process payments for certain transactions. These third parties comply with similar and equally stringent undertakings of privacy and confidentiality.

We may disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request and to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

We share your personal information with our other Fortive Group companies for internal reasons, primarily for business and operational purposes

As we continue to develop our business, we may sell or purchase assets. If another entity acquires us or merges with us your personal information will be disclosed to such entity.

If any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, all such information will be considered an asset of ours and as such it is possible they will be sold or transferred to third parties.

Where required we share your personal information with third parties to comply with a legal obligation; when we believe in good faith that an applicable law requires it; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; to detect and protect against fraud, or any technical or security vulnerabilities; to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property, safety, or security of third parties, visitors to the our website, our business or the public.

No third parties have access to your information unless we specifically say so in this Privacy Notice, or the law requires this.  
  
What legal basis do we have for using your personal data?  
---  
  
We process your information:

  * To be able to provide you with products and services in line with our Terms & Conditions via the Accruent website.
  * As this is necessary for the performance of the contract with you for or to take steps at your request prior to entering into this contract
  * To comply with our legal obligations
  * To protect your vital interests and the vital interests of others.
  * As this is necessary for us to carry out our functions as a global business, and this includes profiling related to your personal data. While there are some risks with this type of activity, on balance, we consider the risk to your rights of data protection is outweighed by the significant benefits in providing Accruent services to a relevant and interested marketplace.
  * We’ve also implemented protections for your rights by [insert other relevant protections.
  * You have the right to object, on grounds relating to your situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning you which is based on legitimate interests. More information and how to exercise it is set out below.
  * If you notify us of any health or disability requirements, then this may involve the processing of more detailed personal data including sensitive data such as health information that you or others provide about you. In that case we always ask for your consent before undertaking such processing and you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. More information on this right and how to exercise it is set out below.
  * On the basis of your consent for us to process your personal data for a particular purpose.

What happens if you do not provide us with the information we request or ask that we stop processing your information?  
---  
  
We have statutory and contractual obligations that require us to process your information. If you don’t provide the information requested, we may not be able to fulfill our contract with you or perform our obligations to you or related others.  
  
Do we make automated decisions concerning you?  
---  
  
No, we do not carry out automated decision making or automated profiling.  
  
Do we use Cookies to collect personal data on you?  
---  
To provide better service to you on our websites, we and our service providers use cookies to collect your personal data when you browse. For information about our use of cookies and how to decline them or turn them off please read our cookie notice available when visiting one of our websites.  
  
What about marketing?  
---  
  
Accruent would like to contact you from time to time about our new similar products and promotional offers by email, text message, telephone, and mail.

Where we have already collected valid marketing permissions from you, you can always unsubscribe or opt out at any time by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link in any of our communication or by contacting us using the details at the end of this Privacy Notice.  
  
Where do we store your personal data? Do we transfer your personal data outside the EEA?  
---  
  
We store your personal data safely at our premises, in contracted storage facilities, with our service providers, or on our servers within the country where we are based and otherwise within the European Economic Area (EEA). We strive to process your information within the country where we collected it or within the EEA. If we or our service providers transfer personal data, where relevant, outside of the EEA, we will always require that appropriate safeguards are in place to protect the information that is transferred. For example, a portion of our centralised Compliance, Marketing, and Finance functions are performed outside of the EEA, in the USA, so we have put in place safeguards to protect personal data exported from the EEA that is processed in or accessed from the USA. **You can obtain a copy of the safeguards in place for such transfers by contacting us using the details at the end of this Privacy Notice.**  
  
How do we keep your personal data secure?  
---  
  
We ensure the security of your personal data by implementing a specific set of technical and organisational security measures that are based on controls published by the **Center for Internet Security**. These controls call for the use of encryption, firewalls, and other measures that ensure we provide a level of security appropriate to the risk presented by a particular situation.  
  
What rights do you have in relation to the personal data we hold on you?  
---  
  
By law, you have a number of rights when it comes to your personal data. Further information and advice about your rights can be obtained from the data protection regulator in your country.  
  
Rights | What does this mean?  
---|---  
1\. The right to be informed | You have the right to be provided with clear, transparent and easily understandable information about how we use your information and your rights. This is why we’re providing you with the information in this Privacy Notice.  
2\. The right of access | 

You have the right to obtain access to your information (if we’re processing it), and certain other information (similar to that provided in this Privacy Notice).

This is so you’re aware and can check that we’re using your information in accordance with data protection law.  
  
3\. The right to rectification | You are entitled to have your information corrected if it’s inaccurate or incomplete.  
4\. The right to erasure | This is also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’ and, in simple terms, enables you to request the deletion or removal of your information where there’s no compelling reason for us to keep using it. This is not a general right to erasure; there are exceptions.  
5\. The right to restrict processing | You have rights to ‘block’ or suppress further use of your information. When processing is restricted, we can still store your information, but may not use it further. We keep lists of people who have asked for further use of their information to be ‘blocked’ to make sure the restriction is respected in future.  
6\. The right to data portability | You have rights to obtain and reuse your personal data for your own purposes across different services. For example, if you decide to switch to a new provider, this enables you to move, copy or transfer your information easily between our IT systems and theirs safely and securely, without affecting its usability.  
7\. The right to object to processing | You have the right to object to certain types of processing, including processing based on our legitimate interests and processing for direct marketing (i.e. if you no longer want to be contacted with potential opportunities).  
8\. The right to lodge a complaint | You have the right to lodge a complaint about the way we handle or process your personal data with your national data protection regulator.  
9\. The right to withdraw consent | If you have given your consent to anything we do with your personal data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time (although if you do so, it does not mean that anything we have done with your personal data with your consent up to that point is unlawful). This includes your right to withdraw consent to us using your personal data for marketing purposes.  
  
How can you make a request to exercise your rights?  
---  
  
To exercise any of the rights above, or to ask a question, contact us using the details set out at the end of this Privacy Notice.  
  
How will we handle a request to exercise your rights?  
---  
  
We’ll respond as soon as we can. Generally, this will be within one month from when we receive your request but, if the request is going to take longer to deal with, we’ll come back to you and let you know.

We usually act on requests and provide information free of charge, but we may charge a reasonable fee to cover our administrative costs of providing the information for baseless or excessive/repeated requests and requests for further copies of the same information. Alternatively, the law may allow us to refuse to act on such requests.  
  
How can you contact us?  
---  
  
If you have questions on the processing of your personal data, would like to exercise any of your rights, or are unhappy with how we’ve handled your information, please contact us here: Attention: Legal Department, 11500 Alterra Parkway, Suite 110, Austin, TX 78758 USA, or at [support@accruent.com](https://support@accruent.com/) **_with subject line: “Attention: Legal - GDPR Request”._**

If you’re not satisfied with our response to any complaint or believe our processing of your information does not comply with data protection law, you can make a complaint to the data protection regulator in your country.
